<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Home</title>
    <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing A/B Test Results</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project8/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project was working to understand the results of an A/B test run by an e-commerce website. The goal was to work through this notebook to help the company understand if they should implement a new page, keep the old page, or perhaps run the experiment longer to make a better decision.
The project was divided into three parts:
 Probability  Statistics were computed to find out the probabilities of converting regardless of page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Bikeshare Data with Python</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project6/</guid>
      <description>This project focuses on pandas library usage and simple statistics methods to perform a rudimentary analysis on the bikeshare data from three major U.S. cities - Chicago, Washington, and New York City - to display information such as most popular days or most common stations.
The program takes user input for the city (e.g. Chicago), month for which the user wants to view data (e.g. January; also includes an &amp;lsquo;all&amp;rsquo; option), and day for which the user wants to view data (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Data Warehouse with AWS Redshift</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project13/</guid>
      <description>A music streaming startup, Sparkify, has grown their user base and song database and want to move their processes and data onto the cloud. Their data resides in S3, in a directory of JSON logs on user activity on the app, as well as a directory with JSON metadata on the songs in their app.
In this project, we are tasked with building an ETL pipeline that extracts their data from S3, stages them in Redshift, and transforms data into a set of dimensional tables for their analytics team to continue finding insights in what songs their users are listening to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Lake with Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project14/</guid>
      <description>A music streaming startup, Sparkify, has grown their user base and song database even more and want to move their data warehouse to a data lake. Their data resides in S3, in a directory of JSON logs on user activity on the app, as well as a directory with JSON metadata on the songs in their app.
In this project, we are tasked with building an ETL pipeline that extracts their data from S3, processes them using Spark, and loads the data back into S3 as a set of dimensional tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Modeling with Apache Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project12/</guid>
      <description>A startup called Sparkify wants to analyze the data they&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting on songs and user activity on their new music streaming app. The analysis team is particularly interested in understanding what songs users are listening to. Currently, there is no easy way to query the data to generate the results, since the data reside in a directory of CSV files on user activity on the app.
They&amp;rsquo;d like a data engineer to create an Apache Cassandra database which can create queries on song play data to answer the questions, and wish to bring me on the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Modeling with PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project11/</guid>
      <description>A startup called Sparkify wants to analyze the data they&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting on songs and user activity on their new music streaming app. The analytics team is particularly interested in understanding what songs users are listening to. Currently, they don&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way to query their data, which resides in a directory of JSON logs on user activity on the app, as well as a directory with JSON metadata on the songs in their app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Hospital Appointments Dataset</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project7/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project was to go through the entire data analysis process utilizing a dataset of our choice and creating a Jupyter NB report that communicated my findings.
This dataset collects information from 100k medical appointments in Brazil and is focused on the question of whether or not patients show up for their appointment. A number of characteristics about the patient and their appointments are included in each row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter API Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project9/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project was to gather data from a variety of sources and in a variety of formats, assess its quality and tidiness, then clean it.
The dataset that we will be wrangling (and analyzing and visualizing) is the tweet archive of Twitter user @dog_rates, also known as WeRateDogs. WeRateDogs is a Twitter account that rates people&amp;rsquo;s dogs with a humorous comment about the dog. These ratings almost always have a denominator of 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sakila DVDrental Database Analysis</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project5/</guid>
      <description>In this project we investigate the Sakila DVD Rental database. The Sakila Database holds information about a company that rents movie DVDs. For this project, the database is queried to gain an understanding of the customer base, such as what the patterns in movie watching are across different customer groups, how they compare on payment earnings, and how the stores compare in their performance.
  Sample slide from project report   This project focuses on gaining on hand experience with exploring a relational database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Detection</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project4/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project was to implement four simple motion detection algorithms, run them on short videos, and compare the results. The four algorithms are:
 Simple Background Subtraction Simple Frame Differencing Adaptive Background Subtraction Persistent Frame Differencing  We were required to implement all four in one program and generate, as output, a four-panel frame showing the results of each algorithm, on each video frame, and generate a video of the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiview Projection</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project was to implement forward (3D point to 2D point) and inverse (2D point to 3D ray) camera projection, and to perform triangulation from two cameras to do 3D reconstruction from pairs of matching 2D image points.
The specific tasks were to project 3D coordinates (sets of 3D joint locations on a human body, measured by motion capture equipment) into image pixel coordinates that we could overlay on top of an image, to then convert those 2D points back into 3D viewing rays, and then triangulate the viewing rays of two camera views to recover the original 3D coordinates we started with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Customer Segments</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>Application of unsupervised learning techniques on product spending data collected for customers of a wholesale distributor to identify customer segments hidden in the data.
We first explore the data by selecting a small subset to sample and determine if any product categories highly correlate with one another. Afterwards, we preprocess the data by scaling each product category and then identifying (and removing) unwanted outliers. With the good, clean customer spending data, we apply PCA transformations to the data and implement clustering algorithms to segment the transformed customer data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Donors for CharityML</title>
      <link>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmanuelfwerr.github.io/MyPortfolioSite/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Application of supervised learning techniques on data collected from the U.S. census to help CharityML identify people most likely to donate to their cause.
We first explore the data to learn how the census data is recorded. Next, apply a series of transformations and preprocessing techniques to manipulate the data into a workable format. We then evaluate several supervised learners on the data, and consider which is best suited for the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
